<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digitization on a j smith</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/digitization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digitization on a j smith</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:08:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/digitization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>quaddresses: imprecision in practice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/quaddress-cont/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/quaddress-cont/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After significant time using quaddresses in a real application, I reflect on their effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>woodhull sentinel digitization and preservation project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/woodhull-sentinel-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/woodhull-sentinel-digitization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the discovery of several hundred newspapers from the 1930&amp;rsquo;s from the Town of Woodhull New York, a plan was developed to digitize and preserve the content. In April 2025, the Town of Woodhull reviewed the project proposal and agreed to fund it. The project will begin Summer 2025 with the vendor &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bslw.com&#34;&gt;Backstage Library Works&lt;/a&gt;, with a goal of completion by the end of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>spatially mapping derivative content to original documents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/quaddress-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/quaddress-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quadrant Addressing or &lt;em&gt;Quaddressing&lt;/em&gt; provides an intuitive and consistent way to make relative spatial references to an original, two dimensional artifact (primarily for documents such as a printed text, photographs, etc.) regardless of its size or shape, or whether the artifact is physical or digital. Quaddressing relies on imprecision to aid human judgement instead of relying on highly precise measurements of varying units across different types of documents, thereby greatly increasing the ease and efficiency of both recording and interpretation across all documents for both human actors and code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
