<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on a j smith</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on a j smith</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 08:45:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pip: Minimal Two-Dimensional Chess Piece Set</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/minimal-chess-pieces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/minimal-chess-pieces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article explores a concept for minimal, two-dimensional chess pieces for use in digital environments. I wanted to create a &lt;em&gt;functional&lt;/em&gt; approach, in which the design of each piece represents its capabilities instead of its name. Similar in appearance to the faces of dice, the arrangement of pips reflects each piece&amp;rsquo;s legal movement pattern.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wine Cube: simple wine bottle storage model</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/wine-cube/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/wine-cube/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wine Cube is a simple, configurable OpenSCAD based system for creating passive, minimal, modular, high density wine bottle storage shelving units. Configuration options include simple ways of changing the dimensions, capacity and bottle orientation of each shelving unit. This project grew out of a personal need for such shelving and a desire to learn CAD. It is an ongoing, open source project that I am releasing early as I have judged it to have reached a stage of being minimally interesting. This project may be useful to someone looking for a very simple, inexpensive and utilitarian approach to wine bottle shelving, in their home, in a location where its stark appearance won&amp;rsquo;t offend, such as a basement or garage area. Its simplicity may also make it a good example project for learning OpenSCAD, as I have tried to keep the code simple, clear and logically organized. This article provides a brief description of Wine Cube, my motivation for creating it, and my reasons for choosing OpenSCAD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cell: minimal geometric font</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/cell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cell is a minimal, geometric, sans-serif, monospace, all caps display font.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
