<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on a j smith</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on a j smith</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>quaddresses: imprecision in practice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/quaddress-cont/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/quaddress-cont/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After significant time using quaddresses in a real application, I reflect on their effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>woodhull sentinel digitization and preservation project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/woodhull-sentinel-digitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/woodhull-sentinel-digitization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the discovery of several hundred newspapers from the 1930&amp;rsquo;s from the Town of Woodhull New York, a plan was developed to digitize and preserve the content. In April 2025, the Town of Woodhull reviewed the project proposal and agreed to fund it. The project will begin Summer 2025 with the vendor &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bslw.com&#34;&gt;Backstage Library Works&lt;/a&gt;, with a goal of completion by the end of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pip: Minimal Two-Dimensional Chess Piece Set</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/minimal-chess-pieces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/minimal-chess-pieces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article explores a concept for minimal, two-dimensional chess pieces for use in digital environments. I wanted to create a &lt;em&gt;functional&lt;/em&gt; approach, in which the design of each piece represents its capabilities instead of its name. Similar in appearance to the faces of dice, the arrangement of pips reflects each piece&amp;rsquo;s legal movement pattern.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wine Cube: simple wine bottle storage model</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/wine-cube/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/wine-cube/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wine Cube is a simple, configurable OpenSCAD based system for creating passive, minimal, modular, high density wine bottle storage shelving units. Configuration options include simple ways of changing the dimensions, capacity and bottle orientation of each shelving unit. This project grew out of a personal need for such shelving and a desire to learn CAD. It is an ongoing, open source project that I am releasing early as I have judged it to have reached a stage of being minimally interesting. This project may be useful to someone looking for a very simple, inexpensive and utilitarian approach to wine bottle shelving, in their home, in a location where its stark appearance won&amp;rsquo;t offend, such as a basement or garage area. Its simplicity may also make it a good example project for learning OpenSCAD, as I have tried to keep the code simple, clear and logically organized. This article provides a brief description of Wine Cube, my motivation for creating it, and my reasons for choosing OpenSCAD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cell: minimal geometric font</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/cell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cell is a minimal, geometric, sans-serif, monospace, all caps display font.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Static Web Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/static-development-streamlining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/static-development-streamlining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are times when even using Hugo for static web development is overkill. This articles shows how to efficiently develop small static web pages with some of the same advantages as the Hugo environment:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Easily invoke a zero-configured static web server.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optimize development efficiency with LiveReload.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Automate the environment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optimize for production.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solutions described will use &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/&#34;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; and Bash scripts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>comparing facial symmetry between photographs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/comparing-facial-symmetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/comparing-facial-symmetry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent research, I received two photographs of unidentified women that were purported family members, and I wanted to explore a structured way of comparing them that could also be easily communicated as a two-dimensional still image for ease of publication/distribution. The following is the approach I took, and although I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this approach is valid, I thought the process and the results were interesting enough to warrant this description.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>spatially mapping derivative content to original documents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/quaddress-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/quaddress-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quadrant Addressing or &lt;em&gt;Quaddressing&lt;/em&gt; provides an intuitive and consistent way to make relative spatial references to an original, two dimensional artifact (primarily for documents such as a printed text, photographs, etc.) regardless of its size or shape, or whether the artifact is physical or digital. Quaddressing relies on imprecision to aid human judgement instead of relying on highly precise measurements of varying units across different types of documents, thereby greatly increasing the ease and efficiency of both recording and interpretation across all documents for both human actors and code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>my process for creating new Hugo sites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/hugo-github-pages-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/hugo-github-pages-workflow/</guid>
      <description>My current documentation, in bash code, for creating a new Hugo site hosted on Github pages.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
